americanfidelity.com 2019-07-19

# Privacy Policy | American Fidelity

Effective July 1, 2018

American Fidelity Assurance Company ("American Fidelity") understands that privacy is an important issue for visitors to our websites at americanfidelity.com, afadvantage.com, afenroll.com, afhsa.com, our other affiliated websites, and our mobile applications. It is the policy of American Fidelity to protect the nonpublic personal information ("personal information") we collect from current, prospective, or former Customers and from visitors to our websites.  We will keep this information secure and confidential. The following statement is provided to help our website visitors understand what information is gathered through our sites and applications and how that information is handled and used once it is gathered. This Internet Privacy Policy applies to our publicly available websites and any subsites (including any password protected sections of those sites).  The Mobile Application Privacy Policy portion of this Policy applies to our mobile applications. If you are an individual who has purchased an insurance product from American Fidelity, you have received or will be receiving in the mail additional information about our privacy practices.  We will make every effort to update this information prior to making any changes to our online privacy practices.  When our online privacy practices do change, we will post the update on this website.  We respect your privacy and promise to treat your personal information responsibly. Your privacy is as important to us as it is to you.

We will not knowingly allow any minor to register for services, attempt to purchase our products, or access any areas which require registration.

## Information We Collect

We collect and maintain information about you so that we can provide you with the insurance coverage and other products and services that you have requested and to protect, service and administer your records, accounts and funds. We may also use your information to help design new or improved products and services. Most importantly, any information that you may agree to provide helps us better understand your financial and insurance needs so we can continue to provide you high quality products and services.

We require you to share your personal information with us for some of our online activities. These activities include accessing your policies online, applying for products or services, and asking us questions. Personal information is any information that identities you and describes your relationship with American Fidelity. Some examples of the personal information that American Fidelity may collect include information:

  * You give us, such as: name, address, age, marital status, Social Security number, annual income, and other financial information. This includes information supplied on an application or to an insurance agent.
  * About your business with us or others. This information is about other products or services you own or use and may be provided to us by you upon our written request.
  * Given by your employer or group plan sponsor for any group product you may have. It is provided in writing or electronically through a secure process.
  * From consumer reporting agencies, such as: credit relationships and history. It is given upon our written request. It includes information that an agency already has on file.
  * From sources outside American Fidelity, such as: medical records; motor vehicle reports, etc. It is provided to us upon our written request. The medical information may be provided by a medical provider you have named, or from the Medical Information Bureau (MIB).
  * From visitors to American Fidelity Nonpublic Online Service Center Website. This is secure data you enter while visiting the website.
  * From a report prepared by an insurance-support group that may be kept by us. It may be disclosed to other persons as permitted by law.

If you apply for a product or service, we may collect information from your consumer reports, such as your credit report or motor vehicle report. We may also need to collect your medical information. We won't use or share your medical or consumer report information for marketing purposes.

## How We Protect Information About You

We maintain appropriate physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to maintain the confidentiality and security of your personal information. We restrict access to personal information about you to those employees who have a need to know that information to provide products or services to you. Physical and electronic files are kept in secure areas. We educate our employees about the importance of confidentiality and customer privacy. We also enforce employee privacy responsibilities. Our handling and protection of your personal information is governed by a range of state and federal laws, rules and regulations. Information you may consent to provide using the Internet is afforded the same protection as it would be if you provided it in writing, by phone or in conversation with one of our representatives. We collect, retain and share your personal information only for particular business-related purposes and only as authorized by state and federal law.  For example, we may share your information with vendors that assist us with account administration or data processing. 

It is our goal to demonstrate American Fidelity's commitment to your privacy and describe our policy for collecting, safeguarding and administering your personal information. Here are our some additional answers to some common questions about privacy and security. We hope this information addresses your concerns. If you have further questions or comments about American Fidelity's Privacy Policy please contact American Fidelity's Privacy Advocate at [1-866-55-HIPAA](tel:1-866-554-4722) ([1-866-554-4722](tel:1-866-554-4722)).

## What do we track and record?

You are not required to provide personal information or reveal your identity to browse our public website.

When visitors access our public pages our web servers log the IP address (the numeric Internet address of a computer). We do not link IP addresses to any personal information. IP address tracking allows us to track a visitor's session but the visitor remains anonymous. This provides information about parts of the site visited and the length of time spent there. We also record the information your browser provides about browser type and version. We use this information to administer our system and improve the information and services offered on our public website.

Information may also be collected by American Fidelity when you voluntarily provide it to us. For example, you may want to apply for certain American Fidelity insurance coverage or simply request additional information concerning one of our products or services. In this case, we collect only the information you voluntarily provide and use it only for the specific purpose it was provided.

## Our Cookie Policy

This website may use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

This website may also use Facebook Pixel or similar remarketing programs that employ tracking cookies.  Remarketing cookies allow us to show ads to you as you visit other websites. 

## Will you honor my Do Not Track requests?

Information about your visit to our website, including any information you provide to us, is aggregated and is never tied to your personal information.  We use Google Analytics as our data tracking and aggregation service.  Google’s terms of use prevent us from sending your personal information (such as name, address, and billing information) to them, and Google does not store or process any personal information that they do receive.  Should you wish to prevent Google from receiving any information regarding your visit to our site, you may visit <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en> to download a tool that will prevent Google Analytics from receiving any information about your visit to this or other websites.  (Please note that this is a third-party service, provided by Google, and not a service created or maintained by American Fidelity.  As such, American Fidelity makes no representation as to the efficacy or usability of this service.)

### What about e-mail addresses?

We only capture the e-mail address of visitors to our public site who request information, select e-mail as the preferred response, and provide us an e-mail address. We do not use e-mail addresses provided in this manner for e-mail mass marketing.

## Mobile Application Privacy Policy

As a service to our customers, we have developed a mobile application that may be used on smartphones and other electronic devices.  To facilitate the processing of claims and reimbursement requests, we may collect personal information including name, contact information, account information, Social Security or policy number, and medical information that appears on any receipts or invoices that are submitted via the mobile application.  Other personal information may also be requested if it is deemed necessary for processing requests made via the mobile application. 

We may collect information regarding your mobile device.    That information could potentially include the IP address of your mobile device, the type of mobile browser in use, your mobile device’s unique ID number, your mobile operating system, and information about the way that you use our application.  We will not collect information about the location of your mobile device without asking your permission.  We will not associate your mobile device information with your personal information in our records.  Any information collected regarding your mobile device would only be used in the aggregate, by us or by a business partner, for application stabilization or enhancement purposes. 

Any information collected via our mobile application will be treated with the same level of care as information submitted to us via other means, and all relevant provisions of our online privacy policy apply to mobile applications as well. 

## How can I contact American Fidelity?

You can contact us regarding privacy as follows:

  * Questions or comments about American Fidelity's Privacy Policy, please contact:   
American Fidelity's Privacy Advocate at [1-866-55-HIPAA](tel:1-866-554-4722) ([1-866-554-4722](tel:1-866-554-4722))
  * To review your information, or to correct or change any information that we have on file, please contact us. 
    * By phone at [800-662-1113](tel:8006621113)
    * By mail at:

American Fidelity Assurance Company  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
PO Box 25523  
Oklahoma City, OK 73125-0523

Download American Fidelity Assurance Company's notices in Adobe PDF format:

HIPAA Notice of Privacy Practices

GLBA Notice

## AGREEMENT

Your voluntary use of our website signifies that you consent to our Internet privacy policy. Should you not consent to our policy, you will need to vacate this website or delete our mobile application immediately. We reserve all rights to modify our Internet privacy policy in the future as we see fit and/or as required by applicable law. However, prior to implementing any changes, we will make every attempt to provide adequate notice on this website.

© Copyright 2018 American Fidelity Assurance Company. All rights reserved.
